Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory10 Mss.B.B61.inventory10
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents N
  - New York University & Bellevue Hospital. New Yorker Staats-Zeitung (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1933? Oct. 27; 1p.
      See Ridder, Hermann
    - New Yorker Staats-Zeitung -- from Heger, F., 1923 Nov. 1; 2p.
  - New York World Telegram (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1935 Jan. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 26; 1p
  - New School for Social Research, Inc. (Box 66)
    See Graduate Faculty of Political and Social Science
    See Kallen, Horace M.
    See Smith, Liv
    See Sussman, Esther B.
  - Newark Academy (Box 66)
    - See Farrand, Wilson-, 4-14-32, 4-20-32, 5-4-32, 10-6-32
  - Newcomb, Simon (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1904 Jan. 12; 2p.
  - Newcombe, Dr. Charles F. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1906 Oct. 24
    - From Boas, 1911 Mar. 13; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1911 Mar. 27
    - From Boas, 1911 Mar. 30
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1897 Feb. 3; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Oct. 2
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 20
    - To Boas, 1908 Feb. 28
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 11
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 21
    - To Boas, 1911 Mar. 17; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Apr. 20; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 19; 1p.
    - Dr. Charles F. Newcombe -- to Hunt, G., 1906 July 5
  - Newcombe, W.A. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 June 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 May 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 14; 2p.
  - Newell, William Wells (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1894 Jan. 20
    - From Boas, 1894 Feb. 24
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Mar. 2
    - From Boas, 1905 June 15
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 6
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Dec. 17
    - To Boas, 1882 Feb. 27
    - To Boas, 1887 Dec. 17
    - To Boas, 1888 Jan. 11
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 4; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 16; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Apr. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Apr. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Apr. 20; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Apr. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Aug. 7; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Aug. 28; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Sept. 13; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Sept.18; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Sept. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Oct. 6; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Dec. 1; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Dec. 18; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1889 Jan. 28
    - To Boas, 1889 Feb. 6
    - To Boas, 1889 Feb. 9
    - To Boas, 1889 Feb. 27
    - To Boas, 1889 Mar. 1
    - To Boas, 1889 Mar. 26
    - To Boas, 1889 Mar. 29
    - To Boas, 1889 Mar. 29
    - To Boas, 1889 Apr. 13
    - To Boas, 1889 Oct. 31
    - To Boas, 1889 Nov. 11
    - To Boas, 1889 Nov. 22
    - To Boas, 1889 Nov. 23
    - To Boas, 1890 Jan. 10
    - To Boas, 1890 Jan. 29
    - To Boas, 1890 Feb. 12
    - To Boas, 1890 Feb. 24
    - To Boas, 1890 Mar. 18
    - To Boas, 1890 May 9
    - To Boas, 1890 May 21
    - To Boas, 1890 Oct. 15
    - To Boas, 1890 Oct. 30
    - To Boas, 1890 Dec. 10
    - To Boas, 1891 Sept.16
    - To Boas, 1891 Nov. 8
    - To Boas, 1892 Jan. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1892 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1892 Dec. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1892 Dec.?; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1893 Jan. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1893 Feb. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1893 Apr. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1893 Aug. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1894 Jan. 23
    - To Boas, 1894 Feb. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1894 Mar. 17
    - To Boas, 1894 May 1
    - To Boas, 1894 May 2
    - To Boas, 1894 May 14
    - To Boas, 1895 Jan. 30
    - To Boas, 1895 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1895 Oct. 31
    - To Boas, 1896 Feb. 5
    - To Boas, 1896 Feb. 27
    - To Boas, 1896 June 10
    - To Boas, 1896 Oct. 12
    - To Boas, 1896 Nov. 4
    - To Boas, 1896 Nov. 10
    - To Boas, 1896 Nov. 13
    - To Boas, 1896 Nov.?
    - To Boas, 1896 Dec. 2
    - To Boas, 1896 Dec. 15
    - To Boas, 1896 Dec. 19
    - To Boas, 1896 Dec. 20
    - To Boas, 1896 Dec. 21
    - To Boas, 1897 Jan. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1897 Feb. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1897 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1897 Feb. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1897 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1897 Apr. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1897 May 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1897 Nov. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1897 Nov. 12
    - To Boas, 1897 Nov. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Jan. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Feb. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Mar. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Mar. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 May 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 June 6; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1898 June 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Oct. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Nov. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Nov. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Nov. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1899 Feb. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1899 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1899 May 19; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1899 May 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1899 Dec. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Nov. 28; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Dec. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Dec. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Dec. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Mar. 1
    - To Boas, 1905 Mar. 1
    - To Boas, 1905 June 12
    - To Boas, 1905 Aug. 1
    - To Boas, 1905 August 4
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 29
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 30
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 4
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 19
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 24
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 28
    - See Anon., Mar. 10, 1907
  - Newlon, Jesse H. (Box 66)
    - See Boas, F. Open letter on culture and democracy in Spain. Replies., Jan., 1938
  - Newman, Montrose (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1937 Dec. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 22; 1p.
  - Newman, Stanley S. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 July 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Sept. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Oct. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 May 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 May 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Aug. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Sept. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Sept.24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Oct. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Feb. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas (open letter), 1941 Nov. 6
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 July 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Oct. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. end
    - (see Boas, F. to Sharp, W.,1931?), 1932 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. end
    - (see Boas, F.-open letter, 1932), 1933 Mar. 20; 1p.
    - (see Boas, F.-open letter, 1933), 1933 Dec. end
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 May 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan.
    - (see Boas, F.-open letter,Mar.13), 1939 July end
    - (see Boas, F.-open letter), 1939 Sept.13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Sept. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Sept.25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Sept.26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. end; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1940 May 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 June 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Sept.27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 16; 1p.
    - Stanley, S. Newman -- to B. Edel, 1939 July 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 17; 1p.
  - Newman, Wilson L. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1927 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 23; 1p.
  - Newton, Ray (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1930 May 13; 1p.
  - Ney, N. L. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 16
  - Niblack, Albert P. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1888 Nov. 15; 3p.
  - Nichols, E. L. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1917 Oct. 18
  - Nichols, Frances S. (Box 66)
    - Frances S. Nichols -- to F.W. Hodge, 1917 Oct. 31
    - Frances S. Nichols -- to F.W. Hodge, 1917 Nov. 1
  - Nichols, Jeanette Paddock (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1923 Apr. 6; 1p.
  - Nicholson, James T. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1940 June 15; 1p.
  - Nicholson, L. DeVere (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 30; 1p.
  - Nicholson, Margaret (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 10; 1p.
  - Nichtenhauser Dora (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1933 May 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 29; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. end; 1p.
    - Dora Nichtenhauser -- from Lienhard Berzel, 1936 Mar. 2
  - Nieber, Prof. (Box 66)
    - Prof. Nieber -- to Ludwig Steltz, 1923 Jan. 29; 1p.
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1936 July 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 22; 1p.
  - Niece, -- (No I.D. Boas' niece) (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1909 June 23
  - Niederlien, Gustavo (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1905 Jan. 17
  - Niederlandischer Komittee zur Erforschung des Ursachendes Weltkrieges (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 3
      (see Japikse, N.)
  - Nielsen, Konrad (Box 66)
    - Konrad Nielson -- to Fridjkof Nansen, 1926 Apr. 11; 6p.
  - Nielson, Yngvar (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1906 Aug. 29; 1p.
  - Nieuwenhuis, A. W. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1924 Jan. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 13; 1p.
  - Niggemeyer, H. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1936 May 13; 2p.
  - Nijhoff, Martinus (Box 66)
    - Martinus Nijhoff -- to Dr. K.G. Wendriner, 1935 Dec. 14; 1p.
  - Nimuendaju, Curt (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Feb. 5; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 27; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 12; 2p.
  - Nissen, Kristian (Box 66)
    - Kristian Nissen -- from F. Nansen, 1926 Apr. 12; 2p.
  - Nixon, H. C. (Box 66)
    - H. C. Nixon -- from J. Mayer, 1931 Sept.15
  - Nobel-Committee of the Royal Caroline Institute (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1935 Sept. end
  - Nobel Peace Prize Committee (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 17; 2p.
  - Nobelkomitee fur Physik (Box 66)
    - Nobelkomittee -- from M.v.Laue, 1933 Aug. 18
  - Noble, Cranford (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1883 no date
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 1
    - To Boas, 1883 May 12
    - To Boas, 1885 July 8; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1885 July 19; 3p.
  - Noble, Enrique (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1940 June 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 13; 1p.
  - Noble, Ruth (Mrs. G.K.) (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1940 June 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 June 16; 1p.
  - Noe, A.C. von (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 7; 1p.
  - Noe, Fletcher M. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1890 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1890 Nov. 20
    - To Boas, 1891 Sept. 26
    - To Boas, 1892 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1892 Dec. 27; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1893 Jan. 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1893 Jan. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1893 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1893 July 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1895 June 19
  - Noeggerath, C.T. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 30; 1p.
  - Noguera, Eduardo (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Sept.18
    - To Boas, 1917 Oct. 9
  - Nolla, J.A.B. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1935 May 15; 1p.
    - J.A.B. Nolla -- to Marshall A. Howe, 1935 Apr. 23; 1p.
  - Nollen, John S. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 23; 2p.
  - Non-Partisan League (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1919 Sept. 5; 1p.
  - Non-Sectarian Anti-Nazi League (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1939 Dec. 5; 1p.
  - Norddeutscher Lloyd Bremen (Box 66)
    also see North German Lloyd
    - To Boas, 1932 Aug. 19; 1p.
  - Norden, E. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1934 June 24; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Solmsen, F. to Dunn,L.C., June 24, 1934)
  - Nordenskiold, Erland (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 22; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Oct. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Dec. 21; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1924 June 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 June 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Sept. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Sept. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 28; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 1; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Dec. 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Sept. 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Oct. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Dec. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Oct. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Dec. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 May 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 May 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 July 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Oct. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 4; 1p.
  - Nordenskjold, Otto (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1925 Oct. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 10; 1p.
  - Norlin, George (Box 66)
    - See Boas, F. Open letter on culture and democracy in Spain. Replies., Jan. 1938
  - Norris, F.T. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1897 Jan. 14; 2p.
  - Norris, George W. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1942 Nov. 9; 1p.
  - Norris, Henry L. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1912 Oct. 21
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 4
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Dec. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1917 June 11
  - North, Eric M. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Apr. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 June 26; 1p.
  - North, Joseph (Box 66)
    - (Enc. with Isserman, A.J., Mar.21, 1941)
    - To Boas, 1941 June 25; 1p.
  - North American Review (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1888 Oct. 22; 3p.
  - North German Lloyd (Box 66)
    also see Norddeutscher Lloyd Bremen
    - From Boas, 1923 May 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Mar. 30; 1p.
  - North Greenland Expedition (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1892 July 7
  - North Pacific Railroad Co. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1886 Aug. 25
  - Northcott, C.H. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr.n.d.; 1p.
    - (enc. originally with Barnes, H.E., July 8, 1918)
  - Northcott, John A. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Sept.10; 1p.
  - Northrup, Belle (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 May 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 7; 1p.
  - Norton, Edmund (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 5; 2p.
  - Norton, Katherine G. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 30
  - Norton, W.W. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1926 July 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 June 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Sept.30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Dec. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Dec. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Feb. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 May 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Sept. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 May 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 May 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 June 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Jan. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 June 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 June 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 June 30
    - To Boas, 1932 Sept.28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Apr. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 May 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 May 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 June 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Sept.12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Sept. 16; 1p.
  - Norton, W.W. and Co. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1937 May 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Sept. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. end
    - To Boas, 1939 July 25
  - Notgemeinschaft der deutschen Wissenschaft (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1928 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 undated; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 10; 5p.
      See Jurgens, A.
      See Schweinitz, D. v.
      See Siegismund
  - Nottmeyer's Hotel (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1901 Jan. 28
  - Novick, Irving (Box 66)
    - Irving Novick -- to B.J. Foss, 1939 Nov. 6; 2p.
    - Irving Novick -- from B.J. Foss, 1939 Nov. 14
  - Novikoff, J. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1926 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 May 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - J, Novikoff -- to M. Hellman, 1920 Oct. 15; 1p.
  - Nowell, C. J. (Box 66)
    - C.J. Nowell -- to H.S. Clements, 1915 Jan. 28; 5p.
  - Noyes, Edward A. (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1934 Sept.18; 1p.
  - Noyes, William A. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Aug. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. end; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - (Enc. Noyes, W. A. to Gaston- Haye, Henri, Dec. 5, 1940), 1941 Aug. 30; 1p.
      General note
    - W.A. Noyes -- to Henri Gaston-Haye, 1940 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Noyes, W.A., Dec.5, 1940)
    - W.A. Noyes -- from C.F. Roos, 1931 May 4
    - W.A. Noyes -- to White, 1931 Mar. 2; 1p.
  - Nuey?? (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1937 May 20; 1p.
  - Nunn (Box 66)
    - To Boas, 1907 June 1
  - Nusbaum, Jessie L. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1931 July 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 July 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 July 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 July 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. end
  - Nussbaum, William (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 May 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Sept. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 May 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 July 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. end; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 27; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Aug. 22; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 8; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 21; 1p.
    - (see Boas, F. to Nussbaum, W., Nov. 23, 1935), 1936 May 12; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1936 May 17; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 19; 2p.
    - See Columbia University Bursar, 1938 July 20
    - To Boas, 1938 July 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Aug. 4; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 2; 1p.
    - William Nussbaum -- from W. Sigcrist, 1932 June 22
  - Nussbaumer, Leo (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 14; 1p.
  - Nute, Grace L. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 July 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Sept.16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept.13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - Grace L. Nute -- to E.C. Deloria, 1942 Nov. 13; 2p.
    - Grace L. Nute -- to R. Hertz, 1932 Mar. 16; 1p.
  - Nutschmann, H. (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1921 Apr. 22; 1p.
    - see Mutschmann
  - Nuttall, Zelia (Box 66)
    - From Boas, 1901 May 16; 6p.
    - From Boas, 1901 May 18
    - From Boas, 1908 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1908 Nov. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1909 Oct. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1909 Oct. 13; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1910 Jan. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1910 Jan. 28; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 14; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Dec. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1901 May 14; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 19; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1909 Sept.27; 8p.
    - To Boas, 1909 Nov. 3; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1910 Jan. 28; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1910 Apr. 6; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Jan. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Oct. 14; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 11; 4p.
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents O
  - O.,D. (Box 67)
    - To Boas, 1923? Mar. 15; 1p.
  - O.?,H.T. (Box 67)
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 13
  - Oak, V.V. (Box 67)
    - To Boas, 1941 Feb. 12; 1p.
  - Oakes, George W. O. (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1926 Sept.27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept.15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept.21; 1p.
  - Ober, Sarah E. (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 5; 1p.
  - Oberholtzer, Ernest C. (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1913 July 8
    - To Boas, 1913 June 14; 2p.
  - Oberlaender, Custav (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1933 Aug. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 28; 1p.
  - Obermaier, Hugo (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1929 Feb. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec. end; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 5; 3p.
  - Oberwager, Charles A. (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 1; 1p.
    - Charles A. Oberwager -- to G. McAneny, 1928 Dec. 21; 1p.
  - O'Brien, Ruth (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1925 May 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 May 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1925 May 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1925 May 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 25; 1p.
  - Obrosehke, D. (Box 67)
    - To Boas, 1913 May 7; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1913 June 30; 1p.
  - Obst, H. (Box 67)
    - To Boas, 1894 Feb. 27; 2p.
  - Ochs, Adolpf (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1932 Feb. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Feb. 5; 1p.
  - O'Connell, Jerry J. (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1938 June 9; 1p.
  - Odets, Clifford (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1941 Nov. 24; 1p.
  - Odum, Howard W. (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1925 May 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Feb. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 May 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Sept.27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 6; 1p.
  - Oehmke, Walter (Box 67)
    - To Boas, 1929 June 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 July 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 July 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Oct. 1; 1p.
  - Oertel, Horst (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 13; 1p.
  - Oestlund, O.W. (Box 67)
    - To Boas, 1909 Dec. 21
  - Oetteking, Bruno (Box 67)
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 30; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1916 May 22
    - Also see FB to Gordon, G.B., May 22 and Dec. 8
    - Also see FB to Dixon, R.B., Dec. 8
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 30; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1916 May 22
    - (see Boas, F. to Gordon, G.B., May 22, 1916)
    - From Boas, 1916 Dec. 8
    - (see Boas, F. to Dixon, R.B., Dec. 8, 1916)
    - From Boas, 1917 Sept. 3
    - From Boas, 1918 May 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 May 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept.7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 June 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 1
    - To Boas, 1916 Mar. 13; 1p.